A Guide to the Washington Irving Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6256-o
Washington Irving Collection 1806-[1951], n. d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6256-o
ca. 52 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1965 Jan 4
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Leaf from Life of Columbus, n. d.; AM, 1 p. (fragment)
  - Notes regarding English life, n. d.; AMs, 5 p.
  - Poem, "An Humble Apology for a Violation of the Laws of Politeness" addressed to Rebecca Gratz(in an unknown hand), AM, 1 p.
- Correspondence
  - Washington Irving to Joseph Gratz, 1806 Jul 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1807 Jun 6; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1807 Jul 19; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1807 Aug 31; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Rebecca Gratz, 1809 Jul 4; ALS, 1 p. w/addr
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1810 Mar 20; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1810 Nov 11; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1810 Dec 28; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Rebecca Gratz to Joseph Gratz, 1811 Mar 15; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1815 May 27; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Henry Brevoort, [1819 Sep]; ALS, 1 p. w/addr
  - John Irving to Abbey Irving, [1820] Mar 4; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Col. Fairman, 1821 Apr 19; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [John Howard] Payne, 1821 Apr 30; ALS, 2 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Miss Lowenstein, 1823 Jul 12; ALS, 2 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Baron Von Lowenstein, 1824 Dec 11; ALS, 2 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, 1827 Oct 8; ALS, 4 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, 1829 Oct 10; ALS, 1 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to unknown, [1829] Oct 19; ALS, 1 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, 1835 Apr 28; ALS, 2 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to George [Ferris], 1836 May 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Edward Everett, 1842 Oct 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to George P[almer] Putnam, [1848] Aug 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to William Graham, 1850 Aug 10; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Editor of the Tribune, 1851 Nov 10; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1852 Feb 5; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Robert Balmanno, 1852 Apr 21; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Henry Ogden, 1852 Jun 16; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to [_____ Corbin], [1854] Nov 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - George Bancroft to Washington Irving, 1855 May 30; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Gustav W. [Lurman], 1855 Sep 25; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Anna K. Hiener, 1857 Feb 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - J. S. Williams to Washington Irving, 1857 Feb; AL, 1 p. (copy)
  - Washington Irving to J. S. Williams, 1857 Mar 4; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Charles King, 1857 Mar 19; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to S. B. Woolworth, 1857 Nov 6; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to the Irving Literary Association, [1858] Jan 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Thomas Aspinwall], Mar 20; ALS, 1 p.
    framed with an engraving of Irving, head and shoulders, and a drawing of Irving, seated
  - Washington Irving to unknown, Apr 25; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ William Sotheby], Aug 13; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Editor of the Knickerbocker, Jan 14; ALS, 3 p. w/addr
  - Washington Irving to John Howard Payne, n. d.; ALS, 1 p. w/addr
- Miscellaneous
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, [1825]; Engraving,
  - [ Rebecca Gratz] head and shoulders (photo of a painting), Print
  - Washington Irving, as an older man, head and shoulders, (two copies of a photograph by Matthew Brady), Print
  - Washington Irving, full face, [1851]; Engraving,
  - Autograph of Washington Irving, 1853 Oct 27; ANS,
  - Petition to [Benjamin] Silliman to deliver lectures in New York, signed by Washington Irving, et al., 1836 Feb 17; ADS, 2 p.
  - Petition to the State Legislature if New York, to found an inebriate asylum, signed by Washington Irving, Printed
  - Regarding Clifton Waller Barrett's purchase of the gold medal presented to Washington Irving by the Royal Society of Literature (two copies of news release), [1951]; Printed,